# Amar Lakshya

+91 9412506677

**a** amar-laksh.github.io **□** amar-laksh

20/2, R.K. Puram Phase-2 Taj Nagari, Agra India - 282001

☑amar.lakshya@xaviers.edu.in

'A Chemical Computer computing on Digital Computers'

# **Projects & Contributions**

C/ASM FOS - MADE TO BE OPEN : github.com/amar-laksh/fOS

- A Monolithic UNIX-like Kernel for the x86 and ARM (Raspberry Pi) platforms.
- ELF Parsing(with kernel parsing), PCI, Serial (ARM), Western Notes for PC Beeper and System Calls.
- Fully Functional Support for GPIO Pins (ARM) wrapped as Arduino-compatible functions.

Python <u>VITAE</u>: github.com/amar-laksh/vitae

· An Esoteric, Interpreted python-built language built entirely with regular expressions.

JavaScript REPLAYCER: addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/replaycer

• A fun Browser Add-on to replace content on the web.

C++ CACHE PATCH (CORE), MOZILLA CONTRIBUTION: git log | grep amar on codebase

· Worked on patching cache entries that expire immediately

Python/Rust FocusTV: github.com/amar-laksh/focustv

 An extremely responsive face detection system which automatically pauses Media(YouTube and VLC Media Player) when you aren't looking.

Bash/Python TRYINGTOKNOWYOUBETTER: github.com/amar-laksh/TryinToKnowYouBetter

 The Election Commission's website leaks data that can be analyzed to effectively locate all registered voters.

#### **Publications**

2015

2017

CROSSED & KNOTTED - INDIA'S FIRST COMPOSITE NOVEL: amazon.in/Crossed-Knotted-Various-Authors/dp/8192997529

• Co-Author of India's First Composite Novel

BEYOND GOOD AND EVIL: amar-laksh.github.io/beyond-good-and-evil

• A paper focusing on the futility of recognizing Good and Evil as deterministic forces in the world.

## **Work Experience**

July 2017 - Sept 2017 JUNIOR DEVELOPER (LINUX) - INTERN: APOGEE TECH GLOBAL INC. (Bangalore)

• Developed a complete, cross-platform React-based Anti-virus suite.

Dec 2017 - Present SOFTWARE ENGINEER (LEAD): NYMBLE LABS (Bangalore)

 Designed the software stack, software architecture and programmed the codebase using C++ and ROS2 for an Automated Cook.

### Education

**BSc. I.T., 3.26/4.00** - 2014-2017 St. Xaviers College, Mumbai - Autonomous

**xii<sup>th</sup>, 81.00**% - 2013-2014 St. Peters' College, Agra **x<sup>th</sup>, 86.00**% - 2011-2012 St. Peters' College, Agra

### References

Ms. Lydia Fernandes
St. Xaviers' College, Mumbai - Autonomous
Professor at St. Xaviers' College
lydia\_fdes@yahoo.co.in, +91 9930280196